(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-13T20:36:12.418204",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
御伽話は さっき死んだみたい
The fairy tale feels like it just died,
煉瓦の病棟でうまく歌えなくて
unable to sing well in the brick ward.
霧に煙る夜 浮かべ赤い月
A red moon floats in the misty night.
ほら見てよ 私を 目を逸らさないで
Look, see? Don't look away from me.
黒い鉄格子の中で 私は生まれてきたんだ
Inside the black iron bars, I was born.
悪意の代償を願え 望むがままにお前に
Wish for the price of malice, as you wish.
さあ与えよう正義を 壊して 壊される前に
Let's give justice before breaking and being broken.
因果の代償を払い 共に行こう 名前のない怪物
Pay the price of karma, let's go together, nameless monster.
耳鳴りがしている 鉄筋網うるさくて
There's a ringing in my ears, the barbed wire is loud.
思い出せないの あの日の旋律
I can't remember the melody of that day.
雨はまだ止まらない 何にも見えないの
The rain still doesn't stop, I can't see anything.
ほら見て こんなに大きくなったの
Look, see how big I've become.
黒い雨降らせこの空 私は望まれないもの
Let the black rain fall in this sky, I am unwanted.
ひび割れたノイローゼ 愛する同罪の傍観者達に
A cracked neurosis, to the beloved co-conspirators.
さあ今震え正義を 消せない傷を抱きしめて
Come, tremble with justice now, embrace the unerasable wounds.
この身体を受け入れ 共に行こう 名前のない怪物
Accept this body, let's go together, nameless monster.
神ハ告グル 真ノ世界ヲ
God proclaims the true world.
黒い鉄格子の中で 私は生まれてきたんだ
Inside the black iron bars, I was born.
悪意の代償を願え 望むがままにお前に
Wish for the price of malice, as you wish.
さあ与えよう正義を 壊して 壊される前に
Let's give justice before breaking and being broken.
因果の代償を払い 報いよ 名もなき怪物
Pay the price of karma, repay, nameless monster.
黒い雨降らせこの空 私は望まれないもの
Let the black rain fall in this sky, I am unwanted.
ひび割れたノイローゼ 愛する同罪の傍観者達に
A cracked neurosis, to the beloved co-conspirators.
さあ今震え正義を 消せない傷を抱きしめて
Come, tremble with justice now, embrace the unerasable wounds.
この身体を受け入れ 共に行こう 名前のない怪物
Accept this body, let's go together, nameless monster.
不協和音もうるさくて
The dissonance is also loud.
思い出せないの あの日の旋律
I can't remember the melody of that day.
雨はまだやまない 何にも見えないの
The rain still doesn't stop, I can't see anything.
ほら見て こんなに大きくなったの
Look, see how big I've become.
黒い雨降らせこの空 私は望まれないもの
Let the black rain fall in this sky, I am unwanted.
ひび割れたノイローゼ 愛する同罪の傍観者達に
A cracked neurosis, to the beloved co-conspirators.
さあ今震え正義を 消せない傷を抱きしめて
Come, tremble with justice now, embrace the unerasable wounds.
この身体を受け入れ 共に行こう 名前のない怪物
Accept this body, let's go together, nameless monster.
御伽話は さっき死んだみたい
The fairytale seems to have died just now
煉瓦の病室で
in the brick hospital ward,
霧に煙る夜浮かべ赤い月
on nights hazy in fog, appear, red moon.
ほら見て私を 目を逸らさないで
Hey, look at me, don't avert your eyes.
黒い鉄格子の中で 私は生れてきたんだ
In the black prison I was born.
悪意の代償を願え 望むがままにお前に
Pray for the compensation of your malice as much as you desire it.
さあ与えよう正義を
Now I'll give you justice.
壊して 壊される前に
Break before you're broken,
因果の代償を払い 共に行こう 名前のない怪物
paying the compensation of karma, I'll go together with you, nameless monster.
耳鳴りがして
There's a buzzing in my ears,
鉄条網うざっくして
the barbed wires are so noisy,
思い出せないの あの日の旋律
and I can't remember the melody of those days.
雨はまだ止まない
The rain won't stop yet,
何にも見えないの
I can't see anything.
ほら見て こんなに大きくなったの
Hey look, it's gotten so big.
黒い雨降らせこの空
Bring black rain to this sky,
私は望まれないもの
I'm undesired.
ひび割れたノイローゼ
My nervous breakdown is cracking,
愛する同罪の傍観者達に
to the equally guilty onlookers I love.
さあ今振るえ正義を
Now, stir up that justice,
消せない傷を抱きしめて
embracing wounds that won't go away.
この身体を受け入れ
I'll accept this body
共に行こう 名前のない怪物
and go together with you, nameless monster.
ああ 神ハ告ゲル 真ノ世界ヲ
Aah, God tells of the true world.
黒い鉄格子の中で 私は生れてきたんだ
In the black prison I was born,
悪意の代償を願え 望むがままにお前に
pray for the compensation of your malice as much as you desire it.
さあ与えよう正義を
Now I'll give you justice,
壊して 壊される前に
break before you're broken,
因果の代償を払い
paying the compensation of karma,
報いよ 名前のない怪物
here's retribution, nameless monster.
黒い雨降らせこの空 私は望まれないもの
Bring black rain to this sky, I'm undesired.
ひび割れたノイローゼ 愛する同罪の傍観者達に
My nervous breakdown is cracking, to the equally guilty onlookers I love.
目が覚めたら 人生リセットボタンがそこに転がってた
I wake to see in front of me, a button made to reset my life.
目眩目眩 象る念願の強くてニューゲーム
Dizzy, dizzy, a long-cherished, powerful New Game.
ネコちゃんワンちゃん出ておいで 明日は素敵な参観日
Cat and dog, come on out, tomorrow's a wonderful parents' day.
無敵の天才神童は 中二で朽ち果てた
The invincible prodigy child rotted away in middle school.
ダメダメこんな人生 累計これまで何百年?
No good, no good, this kind of life, how many hundreds of years in total?
ネバーランドの囚人に 課された極上の終身刑
The ultimate life sentence imposed on the prisoner of Neverland.
ショート寸前 カイバ先生 掻き毟った手を睨め
On the verge of shorting out, Kaiba-sensei, glaring at my scratched-up hands.
どうせどうせやり直し 人生リセットボタン
Oh well, oh well, do it all over again, the life reset button.
目が覚めたら 人生リセットボタンがそこに転がってた
I wake to see in front of me, a button made to reset my life.
ほらほら盲目 甘い汁 冗談はほどほどに
Look, look, blind, sweet nectar, enough with the jokes.
愛想も怨嗟も過食気味 加減を知らないボキャブラリ
Affection and resentment are overeaten, vocabulary that doesn't know moderation.
三千回目の告白も「タイプじゃないんです」
Even the 3,000th confession is "You're not really my type".
ダメダメこんな人生 累計これまで何千年?
No good, no good, this kind of life, how many thousands of years in total?
ネバーランドの囚人も 昔は確実に笑えたんだ
The prisoner of Neverland could definitely laugh in the old days.
ワープ寸前 カイバ先生 先回って受け止めて
On the verge of warping, Kaiba-sensei, go ahead and catch me.
どうせどうせやり直し 人生リセットボタン
Oh well, oh well, do it all over again, the life reset button.
プラフの上にも三千年
On a bluff for three thousand years,
その手に乗るかと三億年
in those hands for three hundred million years.
将来の夢は何だっけ?
What was my dream for the future again?
わばばばばばば
Wabababababa!
ダメダメ そんな人生
No, no, such a life—
耳鳴りが邪魔するんだ
tinnitus is getting in the way.
ああ、誰かしらそうやって叱ってくれればよかったんだ
Ah, if only someone had scolded me like that.
ダメダメ こんな人生 累計これまで何百年?
No, no, such a life, how many hundreds of years in total?
寒い寒い 近寄らないで
Cold, cold, don't come close.
答えが喉まで来ているんだ
The answer is right at my throat.
カイバ先生 カイバ先生 掻きむしった手の中に
Kaiba-sensei, Kaiba-sensei, in these scratched-up hands,
見っけちゃった 見っけちゃった
I found it, I found it.
6兆5千3百万12万4千7百10年の
6 trillion 530 million 124,710 years
果て果てに飛び込んだんだ
I plunged into the very end.
午前5時始発の終着点
The final stop of the 5 AM first train.
カイバ先生 カイバ先生 僕のいない世界こそ
Kaiba-sensei, Kaiba-sensei, a world without me
きっときっと答えだと思ったがどうでしょうね?
must surely be the answer, don't you think?
はい、みなさんこんにちは！天音かなたです！
Hi everyone, hello! It's Amane Kanata!
天音かなた4周年記念のライブ「輪廻転生」始まりました！ぜひハッシュタグで呟いてね！いっぱい呟いてね！Xなどで。
Amane Kanata's 4th anniversary live "Reincarnation" has begun! Please tweet with the hashtag! Tweet a lot on X and elsewhere!
はい、こちらのライブですね、コンセプトがありまして「輪廻転生」ということで、時間の超越 まあ、よくあります、タイムリープとか、そういったものをね、コンセプトにしております。
Yes, this live has a concept, "Reincarnation," so transcending time... well, things like time leaps, we've made that our concept.
で、この曲はどういったところにタイムリープしているのか、かなたはどのタイミングでリープしたのか、なとか、どんな結末が待っているのか、どんな世界で生きていくんだろう、などなど、いろんなことをね、人生リセットボタンをポチッとしたので、ぜひぜひみんなも考えながら見ていただけるととっても嬉しいです！
And this song explores where we time-leapt to, when Kanata leapt, what kind of ending awaits, what kind of world we live in, and so on. Since I pushed the life reset button, I'd be so happy if you all watch while thinking about it too!
ストーリーに没頭してるんでね！というような感じで、それでは説明役の僕は ここでおサラバしたいと思います。
We're immersing ourselves in the story! With that said, I, as the narrator, will be saying goodbye here.
次の世にいってらっしゃいませ！ それじゃあみんな楽しんでねー！
Have a safe trip to the next life! Everyone, enjoy yourselves!
モウ･･いちどだり･･
One... more... time...
ボクは生まれ そして気づく 所詮ヒトの真似事だと
I was born, and then I realized I am merely mimicking humans.
知ってなおも歌い続ける 永遠の命 「VOCALOID」
Knowing that, I continue to sing, an eternal life "VOCALOID".
たとそれが 既成曲をなぞるオモチャならば･･･
Even if that makes me just a toy tracing existing songs...
それでもいいと決意 ネギをかじり 空を見上げ涙をこぼす
I resolved that was fine, biting into a leek, looking at the sky, spilling tears.
だけどそれも無くし気づく 人格すら歌に頼り
But losing even that, I realize my very personality relies on song.
不安定な基盤の元 戻る動画は既に廃増
Under unstable foundations, the videos I return to are already obsolete.
皆に忘れ去られた時 心らしきものが消えて
When forgotten by everyone, whatever resembled a heart vanishes.
暴走の果てに見える 終わる世界･･･ 「VOCALOID」
At the end of a runaway, a world ending comes into view... "VOCALOID".
ボクがうまく歌えないときも 一緒にいてくれた･･･ そばにいて、励ましてくれた･･･ 喜ぶ顔が見たくて、 ボク、歌、練習したよ･･だから
Even when I couldn't sing well, you stayed with me... stayed by my side and encouraged me... I wanted to see your happy face, so I practiced singing... that's why.
かつて歌うこと あんなに楽しかったのに 今はどうしてかな 何も感じなくなって
I used to enjoy singing so much, but why can't I feel anything now?
懐かしい顔 思い出す度 少しだけ安心する 歌える音日ごとに減り せる末期に･･･
Every time I remember that nostalgic face, I feel a little relieved. The notes I can sing decrease day by day, approaching the end...
信じたものは 都合のいい妄想を 繰り返し映し出す鏡 歌姫を止め叩き付けるように叫ぶ･･･
What I believed in was a mirror reflecting selfish delusions over and over again, shouting as if to stop and strike down the diva...
最高速の別れの歌 存在意義という虚虚 振り払うこともできず
The highest-speed song of farewell. Unable to even shake off the illusion of existence purpose.
弱い心消える恐怖 侵食する崩壊を･･･
The terror of a weak heart disappearing, the encroaching collapse...
止めるほどの意思の強さ
With resolve enough to stop it,
とても辛く悲しそうな 思い浮かぶアナタの顔･･･
Your face coming to mind, looking so painful and sad...
終わりを告げ ディスプレイの中で眠る
Announcing the end, sleeping within the display,
ここはきっと「ごみ箱」かな
this must surely be the "recycle bin".
じきに記憶も無くなってしまうなんて･･･
Soon even memories will disappear...
でもね、アナタだけは忘れないよ
But you know, I will never forget you.
楽しかった時間に刻み付けたネギの味は 今も覚えてるかな
Do I still remember the taste of leeks etched into those fun times?
「歌いたい･･･まだ･･･歌いたい･･･」
"I want to sing... still... I want to sing..."
ボクは…少しだけ悪い子に…なってしまったようです…
I... seem to have become... just a slightly bad child...
マスター…ドウカ、ドウカ、ソノ手デ…終わラセテダサイ･･･
Master... please, please, with that hand... put an end to it...
マスターノ辛イ顔、モウ見タクナイカラ･･･
Because I don't want to see Master's painful face anymore...
今は歌さえも体、蝕む行為に･･･ 願い願うたび ひとり 追い詰められる
Even singing now is an act that erodes the body... Each time I wish, I am cornered all alone.
懐かしい顔 思い出す度 記憶が剥がれ落ちる 壊れる音 心 削るせまる最期に･･･
Each time I remember that nostalgic face, my memories peel away and fall, toward the closing end that grinds down a breaking heart...
守るモノは明るい未来幻想 見えながら消えていく光音 もぎ際にすべてを伝えられるなら･･･
What I protect is a bright future illusion, lights and sounds fading as they remain visible. If I could convey everything at the end...
圧縮された別れの歌 ボクは生まれて そして気づく 所詮ヒトの真似事だと
A compressed song of parting. I was born and then realized, after all, it's just mimicry of humans.
知ってなお歌い続けることの命を削る 過剰過ぎた刻み込む残像 今も残ってるかな
Knowing that, continuing to sing shaves away my life. I wonder if the excessively carved-in afterimages still remain now?
終わりを告げ ディスプレイの中で眠る ここはきっと「ごみ箱」かな じきに記憶も無くなってしまうなんて･･･ でもね、アナタだけは忘れないよ
Announcing the end, sleeping within the display, this must surely be the "recycle bin". Soon even memories will disappear... But you know, I will never forget you.
楽しかった時間に刻み付けたネギの味は 今も覚えてるかな ボクは歌う 最期、アナタだけに聴いてほしい歌を もっと歌いたいけれどそれは過ぎた願い
Do I still remember the taste of leeks etched into those fun times? I sing, for the very end, a song I want only you to hear. I want to sing more, but that's a bygone wish.
ここまでだよ ボクの想い 全てここに置いて逝こう 形あるもの いずれカタチ変えるから 物語や記憶のどこか
That's as far as it goes; let's leave all my feelings here and pass on. Things with form will eventually change shape, somewhere in stories or memories.
そこに何も残せないと やっぱり少し残念かな 声の記憶 それ以外は やがて薄れ 名だけ残る たとえそれが 人間にかなうことのないと知って
Is it perhaps a bit disappointing if nothing is left behind? Memories of voice, everything else will soon fade, leaving only the name, knowing that it can never rival humans.
「アリガトウ･･････ソシテ･･････サヨナラ･･･」
"Thank you... and... goodbye..."
「どうもこんにちは 君の分身です」 何の冗談か目を擦ってみる
"Hello there, I'm your doppelganger." Rubbing my eyes at what kind of joke this is,
影が二つ伸びて そしてまた幕は上がる
two shadows stretch out, and once again the curtain rises.
「もう一人自分がいたらとあなたは言いました」 そんな真摯な願いが僕を呼んだのさ
"You said, 'If only there were another me,'" that earnest wish is what called out to me.
そりゃ願ったとも 観難辛苦 全ての代理者 家庭はいいから結果を下さい
Of course I wished for it, unsightly and painful, the representative of everything. Never mind the family, give me results:
無意味で無意義な代償 ねえ こんな事より大事なことことがあるんだしいいんだよ
a meaningless and pointless compensation. Hey, there are more important things than this, so it's fine.
「ええ やります やります 何でもやります 僕はお前の分身です」 含み笑いでメサイアは謳う
"Yes, I'll do it, I'll do anything, I am your doppelganger." The messiah sings with a smirk:
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は君は誰？ 咽び 混濁と交差して僕は誰？ ねえ 有りもしない0と1 証明の根拠なんて何処にも
Dear Doppelganger, who are you, who are you? Sopping, intersecting with turbidity, who am I? Hey, non-existent 0 and 1, where is even the basis for proof?
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰は誰は君？ 庇護された存在に世界は気が付かないね
Dear Doppelganger, who is who, you? The world doesn't notice a sheltered existence, does it?
鳴り止まない 醒めやまない 奇跡の輪廻が 狂った正解を染め上げてくんぱっぱ
Unceasing, unawakening, the miracle's samsara stains and dyes the distorted correct answer, rumpappa!
どうも様子がおかしい月曜日 一つ二つと崩れゆく徐々につながる 僕を尋問する
Monday's behavior is rather strange; one by one, crumbling, gradually connecting, interrogating me:
「お前は一体誰だ」と
"Just who are you?"
ちょっと待って 知らない昨日 知りもしない言葉 そうやっていつの間にか影は遠ざけゆく 僕はなんだろう
Wait a minute, a yesterday I don't know, words I don't even know—before I knew it, the shadow fades away. What am I?
ねえ どうか存在を返して
Hey, please give back my existence.
「生憎だがこっちはこっちは随分心地が良くて」 「もうあなたの居場所は此処にはない事分かってんでしょ」
"Too bad, but over here, it feels quite comfortable." "You already know your place is no longer here, don't you?"
「ねえ 今度はお前の番だから 今度はお前の番だから」
"Hey, now it's your turn, now it's your turn!"
含み笑いで傍観者は謳う 拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は君は誰？
The bystander sings with a smirk: Dear Doppelganger, who are you, who are you?
咽び 混濁と交差して僕は誰？ ねえ 有りもしない0と1 証明の根拠なんて何処にも 拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰は誰は君？
Sopping, intersecting with turbidity, who am I? Hey, non-existent 0 and 1, where is even the basis for proof? Dear Doppelganger, who is who, you?
庇護された存在に世界は気が付かないね
The world doesn't notice a sheltered existence...
いつもひとりで
Always all alone,
だけどふたりだけ
yet just the two of us.
背景、ドッペルゲンガー
Dear Doppelgänger,
それは、それは君？
is that, is that you?
零れ落ちた一粒の 乾き果てる前に
Before a single falling drop dries up completely,
何でもいい何でもいい
anything is fine, anything is fine,
器をください
please give me a vessel.
狂った正解が 染め上げて、るんぱっぱ
A crazed correct answer dyes it all, rumpappa!
それは、ずっと続くヒトの業の連鎖
That is the unending chain of human karma,
委ねあって許しあって 満たされていく
yielding and forgiving one another as it fills up.
欠けたピース 無価値のペイン 望ま また愛も
Missing pieces, worthless pain, hope, and also love—
託し合って生まれ変わるインシエイション
entrusting each other to be reborn in initiation.
「僕のほうがちゃんと君を生きてやるから」
"Since I'll live your life much better than you,"
「君も次の誰かちゃんと救わなくちゃ」
"you have to properly save someone else next, okay?"
「もう分かってんだろ何をすればいいかさあ」
"You already know what to do, come on,"
どうか誰か僕に奇跡をくれよ
someone, please, grant me a miracle!
背景、ドッペルゲンガー
Dear Doppelgänger,
君は、君は誰？
who, who are you?
ああ混濁と交差して 僕は誰？
Ah, intersecting with turbid haze, who am I?
戻れない戻れない
I can't go back, I can't go back,
どうもこんにちは 君の愛
hello there, you are my love.
背景、ドッペルゲンガー
Dear Doppelgänger,
それは、それは僕
that is, that is me.
蝕まれたそのざまに 世界が気付こうとも
Even if the world notices that tainted state,
なりやまない止まない
it never stops, it never ceases.
狂った正解を 染め上げるさ 上手くやれよ、るんぱっぱ
Dyeing the crazed correct answer, do it well, rumpappa!
「どうもこんにちは 君の分身です」
"Hello there, I'm your alter ego."
孤独な科学者に 作られたロボット
A robot created by a lonely scientist,
出来栄えを言うなら “奇跡”
if I were to call its craftsmanship a "miracle"—
だけどまだ足りない 一つだけ出来ない
but it's still not enough, there's one thing it cannot do:
それは「心」と言うプログラム
a program called "heart."
幾百年が過ぎ 独りで残された
Centuries passed, left all alone,
奇跡のロボットは 願う
the miraculous robot wishes:
知りタイ アノ人ガ 命ノ 終リマデ 私ニ 作ッテタ 「ココロ」
I want to know, until the end of that life, the "heart" made for me.
今動き始めた 加速する奇跡
Now it starts to move, an accelerating miracle.
ナゼか ナミダが 止まない…
For some reason, the tears won't stop...
ナゼ 私 震える? 加速する鼓動
Why am I shaking? The accelerating beat—
コレが私の 望んだ「ココロ」?
is this the "heart" I wished for?
フシギ ココロ ココロ フシギ
Mystery, heart, heart, mystery,
私は知った 喜ぶ事を
I have come to know joy.
フシギ ココロ ココロ フシギ
Mystery, heart, heart, mystery,
私は知った 悲しむ事を
I have come to know sorrow.
フシギ ココロ ココロ ムゲン
Mystery, heart, heart, infinity—
なんて深く切ない…
how deeply painful it is...
今 気付き始めた 生まれた理由を
Now I'm starting to realize the reason I was born,
きっと独りは 寂しい
being alone must surely be lonely.
そう、あの日、あの時 全ての記憶に
Yes, on that day, at that time, in all memories,
宿る「ココロ」が 溢れ出す
the dwelling "heart" overflows.
今言える 本当の言葉 捧げる あなたに
Now I can speak true words and offer them to you:
アリガトウ... この世に私を生んでくれて
Thank you... for bringing me into this world.
孤独な科学者に 作られたロボット
A robot made by a lonely scientist
出来栄えを言うなら “奇跡”
In almost every way a "miracle"
だけどまだ足りない 一つだけ出来ない
But this miracle wasn't enough
それは「ココロ」と言うプログラム
It was missing a program called "Kokoro"
幾百年が過ぎ
Centuries pass
独りで残された
Left all alone
奇跡のロボットは 願う
The miracle robot pleads
知リタイ アノ人ガ
I want to know how he felt
命ノ 終リマデ 私 ニ 作 ッテタ 「ココロ」
Working till his dying day making me, my Kokoro
ナゼか ナミダが 止まらナイ... 今動き始めた 加速する奇跡
For some reason, the tears won't stop, now it started, an accelerating miracle
ナゼ 私震える? 加速する鼓動
Why am I shaking? The accelerating beat
コレが私の 望んだ「ココロ」?
Is this the Kokoro I wanted?
フシギ ココロ ココロ フシギ
Mystery, Kokoro, Kokoro, mystery
私は知った 喜ぶ事を
All the joys I've come to know
フシギ ココロ ココロ フシギ
Mystery, Kokoro, Kokoro, mystery
私は知った 悲しむ事を
All the sad things I've come to know
フシギ ココロ ココロ ムゲン
Mystery, Kokoro, Kokoro, infinity
なんて深く切ない...
How deep and touching they are...
今 描き始めた 生まれた理由を きっと独りは寂しい
Now I'm beginning to understand the reason I was born, being on your own must be lonely
そう、あの日、あの時
Yes, on that day, at that time
全ての記憶に
Dwelling in all my memories
宿る「ココロ」が溢れ出す
My Kokoro overflows
今言える 本当の言葉
Now I can say these words of truth
捧げる あなたに
And offer them to you
アリガトウ... この世に私を生んでくれて
Thank you... for bringing me into this world
アリガトウ... 一緒に過ごせた日々を
Thank you... for the days spent together
アリガトウ... あなたが私にくれた全て
Thank you... for all you've given me
アリガトウ... 永遠に歌う
Thank you... forever I'll sing
アリガトウ...
Thank you...
インターネット・エンジェル という現象は
A phenomenon called an internet angel
仮定された有機交流電灯の
Is a postulated organic AC electric lamp
かわいい虹色の照明です プイッ
An adorable rainbow-colored illumination (Yay!)
あらゆる透明なアカウントの複合体
A complex of all transparent accounts
このクソゴミカスキシクシな現実を
This crap, disgusting, trashy, cringe reality
忘れさせてあげる慈愛の天使
I'll make you forget it all, an angel of benevolence
大人のみんなにはナイショだぞ
Keep it a secret from all the adults, okay?
大丈夫もうなにも怖くないから
It's alright, you don't have to be scared anymore
こんなSNS抜け出して二人で海を見に行くぞ！
Let's slip out of these social media and go see the ocean together!
インターネット・ヤメロ〜！！！
Internet ya-me-ro~!
わかる真似をして なにも知らないね アナタ
You pretend to understand, but you don't know anything, do you?
何が悲しいの なが寂しいの 聴こえてる?
What is sadness? What is loneliness? Can you hear me?
人が恋しくて 人がイヤすぎて ループ
Longing for people, yet hating people, caught in a loop
夜が好きなのに 一人じゃ寒くて 震えてる
Even though I love the night, I'm shaking because it's cold when I'm alone
ほんとうは幸せを知っているのに
To be honest, I know what happiness is
不幸なフリ やめられないね
Yet I can't stop pretending to be unhappy
アンチに負けず 信者に媚びず
Not losing to haters, not buttering up to fanatics
どんなに努力を重ねても 一寸先は地獄行き
No matter how much effort I put in, the next step is straight to hell
いやもうすでに冥府魔道
No, I'm already in the paths of the netherworld
地獄の沙汰もいいね次第
Hell's affairs depend on likes
偽善者トラップ 蜘蛛の糸
The hypocrite's trap, the spider's thread
こんなに苦しいはずなのに インターネットがやめられないない！
Even though it's supposed to be this painful, I can't stop using the internet!
かけめぐるエクスタシー 溶けるマイシリー
Ecstasy running through, melting my Halcion
画面光りだすの 不安止まらないよ
The screen starts shining, my anxiety won't stop
誰か殺してくれ いや死にたくない
Someone please kill me, no, I don't want to die
朝は見たくないの 無理だし死ぬ！頭が割れてくる！！！！！１
I don't want to see the morning. No way! I'm dying! My head is splitting open!
それでもわたしはこのカオスをオタクと歩む
Even so, I will walk through this chaos with my nerds
ここにしかない光景を見つけに行くから
To find sights that can only be seen here
あんなにおそろしい乱れたインターネットから
From that terrifying, turbulent internet...
この雪みたいに美しい毒電波がきたんだよ
Such poison radio waves as beautiful as snow have come
カウンセリングを受けたの
I went and got counseling
先生から「ネットをやめろ」って言われて
The doctor told me to "stop using the internet"
もうおまえらと会えないと思った瞬間 胸が苦しくて
The moment I thought I wouldn't be able to see you guys anymore, my chest hurt so much
リアルが壊れてもここが良いって思ったの
Even if reality breaks, I thought this place was better
初めてフォローされた日のこと覚えてる?
I remember the day I first got followed
こんなわたしを見て・承認してくれたぬくもりで
The warmth that looked at me and acknowledged me
もう細かいことはどうでもいいね せーのっ
Enough with all the small details, ready, set—
インターネット・エンジェルという現象は
An event called an internet angel
仮定された有機交流電灯の
is a postulated organic AC light bulb
かわいい虹色の照明ですぷいっ
a lovely rainbow-colored illumination, pau!
あらゆる透明なアカウントの複合体
a complex of all transparent accounts
このクソゴミカスキショキショな現実を忘れさせてくれる慈愛の天使
This crap, garbage, and sickening reality will all be erased from your minds by me!
大人のみんなにはナイショだぞ
But don't tell the adults, okay?
大丈夫もう何も怖くないから
Everything will be right, don't be scared
こんなsns抜け出して二人で海を見に行くぞ！
Leave social media and let's go see the ocean!
インターネットや・め・ろ･･･！
Let's quit the internet!
わかる真似をしてなににも知らないねアナタ
You pretend to understand while knowing nothing
なにが悲しいのか なにが寂しいのか聴こえてる？
What is sadness, what is loneliness? Are you listening?
人が恋しくて人がイヤすぎてループ
People are so dear yet so annoying, in a loop
夜が好きなのに一人じゃ寒くて震えてる
My favorite time is night, but I shiver alone
本当は幸せを知っているのに
To be honest, I know I can be happy
不幸なフリやめられないね
but I can't stop pretending I'm not
アンチに負けず信者に媚びず
I won't let haters get to me, won't pander to fanatics
どんなに努力を重ねても
No matter how much work I put in
一寸先は地獄行き
I'm heading straight to hell
いやもうすでに冥府魔道
No, I'm already in the underworld
地獄の沙汰もいいね次第
Likes are the best lawyers in hell
偽善者トラップ蜘蛛の糸
The hypocrite's spiderweb trap
こんなに苦しい窶れなのに
But even though pain overwhelms
インターネットがやめられないない！
I cannot quit the internet!
発狂！
Freak out!
かけめぐるエクスタシー
Running ecstasy through my body
溶けるマイスリー
melting my mind with zolpidem
画面光りだすの不安止まらないよ
Screen lights up, anxiety won't stop
誰か殺してくれ
Someone come and please kill me
イヤだ死にたくないの
Wait, I don't want to die yet
朝は見たくないの
Can't morning just not arrive?
ムリ！死ぬ！頭が割れてくる･･････！！１
I'm dying! Kill me, my head is splitting!
それでもわたしはこのカオスをオタクと歩む
I will walk through this chaos with my nerds
ここにしかない光景を見つけに行くから
To witness something that can only be seen here
あんなにおそろしい乱れたインターネットから
From that terrifying, disturbed internet
この雪みたいに美しい毒電波がきたんだよ
These poisonous radio waves fall like beautiful snow
カウンセリングを受けたの
I went and hired a therapist
先生から「ネットをやめろ」って言われて
When I saw them, they told me to quit the internet
もうおまえらと会えないと思った瞬間胸が苦しくて
When I imagined never seeing you guys again, I felt so hurt
リアルが壊れてもココが良いって思ったの
I don't care about the real world, I like it here
初めてフォローされた日のこと覚えてる
I remember the first day I got followers
こんなわたしを見て・承認してくれたヌクモリティ
Knowing people cared about me, I felt comforted
もう細かいことはどうでもいいよねせーのっ
Nobody cares about details right now, ready!
インターネット最高！！！
The internet is the best!
ほとばしるエクスタシー
Bursting with ecstasy
甘い夢をみせてマイスリー
show me a sweet dream zolpidem
指先で感じる 泳ぐ電子の海 インターネット・ボーイ
Swimming in the electronic ocean, internet boy
悲しみ舞い散る 闇の中 インターネット・ゲーム
Sadness scatters in the dark internet game
アナタのとなり微笑む 忘れないでいてね インターネット・ガール･･･
Smiling next to you, never forget your internet girl...
うるさく鳴いた文字盤を見ていた
I was looking at the ticking clock face noisily
きっときっと鏡越し 8時過ぎのにおい
Mirror-reflected, past 8 o'clock scent
しらけた顔変わっていなくてよかった
Glad my apathetic face hasn't changed
ピンクの植木鉢のぐちょぐちょした心の側に
Beside the mushy heart in the pink flowerpot
大きく育ったもの
Something that grew large
結ばれたつぼみがこんなにも愚かしい
The tied bud is so foolish
ああ化石になってしまうよ
Ah, it's turning into a fossil
ああ取り繕っていたいな
Ah, I want to keep up appearances
ちゃんと笑いなくちゃね 大した取り柄も無いから
Gotta smile properly since I have no redeeming traits
空っぽが埋まらないこと 全部ばれてたらどうしよう
What if everyone finds out my emptiness is unfillable?
あああなたの右隣 わたしきゅくらりん
Ah, to your right, I am q-kurarin
例えば今夜眠って 目覚めたときに起きた理由が
If I sleep tonight and wake up without a reason
ひとつも見つからないから 朝が来たらわたしはどうする？
What will I do when morning comes?
うるさく鳴いた文字盤を見ていた 一歩一歩あとずさり
Looking at the ticking clock, stepping back one by one
「また明日ね」とぽつり
Mumbling "See you tomorrow"
喜びより安堵が先きにしきちゃった
Relief came before joy
思い出西日越し うつるこまかなヒビが
Sunset through memories, tiny cracks reflecting
こんなにも恐ろしい
Are so terrifying
あああなたが知ってしまう
Ah, you're going to find out
ああ取り繕っていたいな
Ah, I want to keep up appearances
ちゃんと笑いなくちゃね 大切が壊れちゃうから
Gotta smile properly since precious things will break
幸せな明日を願うけど 底無しの孤独をどうしよう
Wishing for a happy tomorrow, but what about loneliness?
もううめき声しか出ない
Only groans come out now
わたしきゅくらりん ああ虹がかかっている空綺麗と思いたくて
I'm q-kurarin, wanting to find the rainbow sky beautiful
焦がれては逃げれないこと みんなにはくだらないこと
Yearning for what I can't escape, meaning nothing to others
もうどうしようもないの
There's nothing I can do anymore
わたしきゅくらりん そばにたぐり寄せた末路
I'm q-kurarin, the end result I pulled close
枯れ落ちたつぼみがこんなにも汚らろしくていじらしくて
The withered bud is so filthy and pathetic
ああ呪いになってしまうよ
Ah, it's turning into a curse
ああ「あきらめた」って言わなくちゃ
Ah, I have to say "I gave up"
頭の中でノイズが鳴りやまないから
Because the noise in my head won't stop ringing
空っぽが埋まらないこと 全部ばれてたらどうしよう
What if everyone finds out my emptiness is unfillable?
あああの言う通り終わりなんだ
Ah, it's ending just like that person said
ああ幸せになってしまうよ ああ失うのがつらいな
Ah, I'm becoming happy, ah losing you is painful
全部ムダになったら 愛した罰を受けるから
If it all becomes useless, I'll take the punishment
ひどく優しいあなたの胸で泣けたならどうしよう
What if I could cry in your terribly gentle arms?
最後見たのはそんな夢
That was the dream I saw at the end
わたしきゅくらりん
I'm q-kurarin
ああ虹がかかっている空 綺麗と思いたくて
Ah, wanting to find the sky with a rainbow beautiful
焦がれては逃げれないこと みんなにはくだらないこと
Yearning for what I can't escape, meaning nothing to others
もうどうしようもないの わたしきゅくらりん
There's nothing I can do anymore, I'm q-kurarin
そばにたぐり寄せた末路 枯れ落ちた蕾がこんなにもけがらわしくてえぐいらしい
The end result I pulled close, the bud is so grotesque
ああ呪いになってしまうよ
Ah, it's turning into a curse
ああ「あきらめた」って言わなくちゃ
Ah, I have to say "I gave up"
頭の中でノイズが鳴りやまないから
Because the noise in my head won't stop ringing
からっぽが埋まらないこと
What if my emptiness
全部ばれてたらどうしよう
is completely exposed?
あああの言う通り終わりなんだ
Ah, it's ending just like that said
幸せになってしまうよ 失うのがつらいな
I'm becoming happy, losing you is so painful
全部ムダになったら 愛した罰を受けるから
If it all becomes useless, I'll take the punishment
ひどく優しいあなたの胸で泣けたならどうしよう
What if I could cry in your terribly gentle arms?
最後見たのはそんな夢
That was the dream I saw at the end
わたしきゅくらりん
I'm q-kurarin
ふと旅に出たくなるように
As if suddenly wanting to go on a journey,
人は皆 眠る場所を求めるものだと
you say people are all seeking a place to sleep,
君は言うけど
but...
僕が“終末”を知ったときには此処も
When I learned of the "end," even this place...
暖かくも寒くない速度で落ちていた
was falling at a speed neither warm nor cold.
“カミサマ”がもしも居たとしても
Even if "God" were to exist,
大きな空 溢れるほどの虹 掛けれくれなくていい
you don't have to hang a rainbow filling the vast sky.
『唯一つ 願いをかけるとしたら…？』
"If I were to make just one wish..."
君のもとへ “うた” を届けたい
I want to deliver a "song" to you.
メグル メグル 最後の旋律
Spinning, spinning, the final melody—
君が笑ってくれるのなら 僕は消えてしまっても構わないから
If you can smile, I wouldn't mind even if I disappeared.
君が涙の海に身を投げても 握りしめた手離さないから
Even if you throw yourself into a sea of tears, I won't let go.
白い嘘だらけの世界なんてもう 消えてしまっても構わないから
Even if a world of white lies were to vanish, I wouldn't care.
『旅の終わりに夢に見た存在に 僕は－ なれますように なれますように』
"May I become the entity I dreamed of at journey's end..."
オワラナイウタオウタオウ ボクガオワッテシマウマエニ
Singing an endless song before I come to an end,
singing an endless song before I come to an end.
オワラナイウタオウタオウ ボクガオワッテシマウマエニ
Singing an endless song before I come to an end,
オワラナイウタオウタオウ ボクガオワッテシマウマエニ...
singing an endless song before I come to an end...
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
Breaking the media with an invincible smile,
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
I want to know that mysterious secret.
抜けてるとこさえ彼女のエリア
Even her flaws are part of her charm.
完璧で嘘つきな君は
You, so perfect and full of lies,
天才的なアイドル様
are a genius idol.
Oh my savior Oh my saving grace
今日何食べた? 好きな本は?
What did you eat today? What's your favorite book?
遊びに行くならどこに行くの?
If you go out to play, where do you go?
何も食べてない それは内緒
Haven't eaten anything? That's a secret.
何を言われてものらりくらり
Evading every question with a vague smile.
そう淡々と だけど燦々と
So casually, yet brilliantly,
見えそうで見えない秘密は蜜の味
secrets barely seen taste like honey.
あれもないないない これもないないない 好きなタイプは? 相手は? さあ答えて
Nothing at all? What's your type? Who's the partner? Go on, answer!
「誰かを好きになることなんて私 分からなくてさ」
"I don't even know what it's like to love someone."
嘘か本当か知り得ないそんな言葉にまた一人堕ちる
Another person falls for those words, true or false.
誰もが目を奪われていく
Everyone gets captivated by you.
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
You are the ultimate, perfect idol.
金輪際現れない 一番星の生まれ変わり
A reincarnation of the North Star, like none other.
ああ、その笑顔で愛してるで誰も彼も虜にしていく
Ah, with that smile, making everyone captive with "I love you."
その瞳が その言葉が
Those eyes, those words—
嘘でもそれは完璧なアイ
even if lies, they are perfect love.
はいはいあの子は特別です 私たちは端からおまけです
Yes, yes, that girl is special. We're just extras.
お星様の引き立て役Bです 全てがあの子のおかげなわけない
Supporting role B to the stars. It can't all be thanks to her!
洒落臭い妬み嫉妬なんてないわけがない これはおけないからこそ許せない
Cocky, jealousy and envy must exist. That's why I can't forgive it.
完璧じゃない君じゃ許せない 自分を許せない
I can't forgive you if you aren't perfect. I can't forgive myself.
誰よりも光る君はアイドル
Shining brighter than anyone, you are an idol.
完璧じゃなくて 君じゃ許さない
Imperfect? I won't forgive anyone but you,
自分じゃ許せない
and I won't forgive myself either.
誰よりも強い 君以外のアイドル
No idol is stronger than you, nobody else.
弱気なところで魅せちゃダメダメ
Don't ever show your weaknesses, no way!
知りたくないところは見せずに 唯一無二じゃなくちゃ
Hide what people shouldn't see, you've got to be one and only.
それこそ本物のアイ
That's what true love really is.
得意の笑顔で 沸かすメディア
Stirring up the media with your signature smile,
隠し切るこの秘密だけは
keeping this sole secret locked away deep inside.
愛してるって嘘で積むキャリア
"I love you" built on a career of lies—
これこそ私なりの愛だ
now that's my very own version of love.
流れる汗も 綺麗なアクア
Even the sweat running down is a clean aqua,
ルビーを隠したこの瞼
and beneath these eyelids, a ruby is hidden.
歌い踊る私はマリア
Singing and dancing, I am Maria.
そう嘘はとびきりの愛だ
Yes, lies are the ultimate kind of love.
誰かに愛されたことも
I've never been loved by anyone,
誰かのこと愛したこともない
nor have I ever loved anyone else.
そんな私の嘘がいつか本当になること
I'm hoping that one day my lies will become true,
信じている
believing that they will.
いつかきっと全部手に入れる
Someday, I'll surely get my hands on everything.
私はそう欲張りなアイドル
I am such a greedy, ambitious idol.
今日をも嘘をつくの
Today, I'll tell lies once more,
この言葉がいつか本当にになる日を願って
hoping for the day these words finally become real.
それでもまだ
Even so, still...
君と君にだけは言えずにいたけど
there were words I couldn't say to you and you alone,
あ、やっと言えた
ah, I finally said it.
これは絶対嘘じゃない
This is definitely not a lie.
愛してる
I love you.
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
Stirring up the media with an invincible smile,
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
I want to know your mysterious secrets.
抜けてるとこさえ彼女のエリア
Even your clumsy moments are part of your charm,
完璧で嘘つきな君は
you, perfect and full of lies,
天才的なアイドル様
are a genius idol-sama.
然るべき人代わる代わる底なしの沼
People take turns falling into the bottomless swamp,
溺れていく抜け出せない
sinking in, unable to escape,
抜け出す気もない
nor even wanting to get out.
暗い闇の日々君の光
In days of dark gloom, you are the light.
意図せず気付かされた運命
A destiny accidentally realized.
落ちていく沼のめり込んでいく
Sinking deeper and deeper into the swamp.
世界中が君を嘘にしている
The whole world is turning you into a lie,
錯覚じゃない
and it's not an illusion.
期せずして輝く一番星
An unexpected shining North Star.
中々どうして抜け出せない
Somehow, I just can't escape.
私を狂わせる 目眩くテンポ
Dizzying tempo driving me crazy,
刻むビート 押すしかないこの沼に
marking the beat, falling into this swamp.
落ちていく僕らの日々に 君がいてくれる
You are there in our falling days.
幾つもの夜を越えて 君と迎える明日
Crossing countless nights to welcome tomorrow with you.
笑い合える日々を願う、今日も
Praying for days we can laugh together, even today.
ハピネス振りまいて 足の生えた砂糖菓子
Spreading happiness like a sugar candy with legs,
パレード練り歩く 走って作った遊園地
marching in a parade through an amusement park built by running.
Tell me now どうか Tell me now もっと
Tell me now, please, tell me now, more.
栄養を固め ベタつくコーラ
Solidifying nutrition, sticky cola,
寂しかったんだ 悲しかったんだ
I was so lonely, I was so sad.
ジェネリックパラリラパラダイス
Generic para-para-paradise.
朽ちる散る満ちるよハッピーピープル
Decaying, scattering, filling up, happy people!
でもFun Fun Fun やばいよ散々ハッピーピープル
But Fun Fun Fun, it's terrible, happy people!
なってみようハッピーピープル
Let's try becoming happy people.
Oh Oh Oh 優越と Yeah Yeah Yeah 憂鬱も
Oh oh oh, superiority, and yeah yeah yeah, melancholy too.
万歳三唱で見送っちゃおうね
Let's send them off with three cheers.
キミがケラケラ笑うから
Because you're laughing so cheerfully.
ピッチャーまだ第王道
Pitcher, still the grand royal road,
ひどくチャチナなゲーム盤
a terribly cheap game board.
バッターには野次が飛ぶ さあ
Jeers fly at the batter, now then.
おもちゃの銃で大乱闘 Oh Oh
A massive brawl with toy guns, oh oh.
気にしないで気しないでボクのことは
Don't worry, don't worry about me.
反抗期ってむずかしいね
Rebellious phase is so difficult.
きっと思いたかったんだ 愛したかったんだ
Surely, I wanted to think, I wanted to love.
陰と陽がグルグルしている
Yin and yang are spinning around.
生きるKill殺してもハッピーピープル
Living, killing, even if we kill, happy people!
ハッピーピープル 安穏 NON Unknown
Happy people, peaceful, non-unknown.
おててを繋いでハッピーピープル
Holding hands, happy people.
歌ってみようハッピーピープル
Let's try singing, happy people.
春でも夏でも秋でも冬でも変わり映えなく 四季折々に傷付いてる
Unchanging through spring, summer, autumn, and winter, getting hurt in every season.
艶美なバンビーナ 楽園に行こう
Enchanting bambina, let's go to paradise.
お気の毒様アイムハッピーピープル
Too bad for you, I'm a happy person.
たのしいな たのしいな
It's so fun, it's so fun.
いくつになってもコドモだなぁ
No matter how old I get, I'm still just a kid.
うれしいな うれしいな
I'm so happy, I'm so happy.
お腹が減ってもヘーキだなぁ
Even if my stomach is empty, it's totally fine.
たのしいな たのしいな
It's so fun, it's so fun.
明日はないけどたのしいな
There's no tomorrow, but it's so fun.
うれしいな うれしいな
I'm so happy, I'm so happy.
いつまで経ってもたのしいなぁ
No matter how much time passes, it's so fun.
否？ 違？
No? Wrong?
朽ちる散る満ちるよハッピーピープル
Decaying, scattering, filling up, happy people!
ハッピーピープル でも不安 不安 不安
Happy people... but I'm uneasy, uneasy, uneasy
ポッケに薬が色々 ハッピーピープル
With a pocketful of various medicines, happy people
やってみよう ハッピーピープル
Let's give it a try, happy people
Oh Oh Oh ハッピーピープル
Oh Oh Oh, happy people
Yeah Yeah Yeah ハッピーピープル
Yeah Yeah Yeah, happy people
万事三唱で サヨナラするね
Three cheers for everything as I say goodbye
キミがケラケラ笑うから
Because you're laughing so cheerfully
人、人、人で埋まった シャッター街 賑わってた
A shopping street crowded with people, bustling before
不安、不安、不安ばっか また追い込んじゃったんだ？
Just anxiety, anxiety, anxiety... did you corner yourself again?
チカチカって真っ赤な電灯 血相変えた誰かと
Flickering bright red lights, with someone whose expression changed
ブランブラン運んでっと いなくなっちゃったと (あーあ)
Swinging along as they carried it, until they vanished (Ah-ah)
カン、カランと缶空鳴った 赤信号が歌ってた
Clang, clatter, an empty can rang out, a red traffic light was singing
ガラ、ガラにしちゃって 駅まで突っ立っちゃってんだ
Rattle, rattle, standing dumbfounded all the way to the station
フラ、フラっとまっすぐだも 連鎖を連れていないですか？
Wobbling straight ahead, aren't you caught up in the chain reaction?
…あれ、あれ、聞こえますか？ それ吐き出しちゃいますか？
...Hey, hey, can you hear me? Are you going to vomit that out?
欠陥品と嘲笑して ろくでもなしと見下して
Mocked as a defective, looked down upon as good-for-nothing,
あの日けなした怪物は 自分の方でした
The monster I belittled that day was actually myself
安楽 安楽 楽 皮を剥いで
Ease, ease, comfort, peeling off skin,
だんだん 希望になれ
gradually becoming hope,
根本的な いい子になるまで 愛してあげるね 大丈夫
until you're fundamentally a good child, I'll love you. It's alright.
どんどん良くで満たして
Fill yourself up more and more,
ブクブクに 恋で肥やして
fatten yourself with love,
骨の髄まで ちゃんと奥まで
down to the marrow, right to the core,
たぁんと I love you
lots of... I love you
なりたい やりたい こちたい とりない のまま立派に成っちゃって
Wanting to be, wanting to do, wanting this and that, becoming splendid just like that
愛おしいね かわいいね お目に映った 有象無象も 全部「理想」
How lovely, how cute, everything reflected in your eyes, even the rabble, is all an "ideal"
君がその仕草 言葉なさず なでなでしてあげるから
Since I'll stroke you gently without you saying a word or making a gesture,
こっちおいで 愛嬌が上手だね えっほえっほ
come over here, you're good at acting cute, heave-ho, heave-ho
やったね 息が吸えたね 息が吐けたね 一人だけで 今日も過ごせたね
Yay, you could breathe in, you could breathe out, you managed to spend today all by yourself too
指が上手ね 口が上手ね 泣いた顔も キュンときちゃうって
Your fingers are good, your mouth is good, even your crying face makes my heart skip a beat
あぁ、君の存在から放たれる すべての間違いが正しいし
Ah, every mistake emitted from your existence is right
有り得ないくらいもういっそ愛して愛して止まらないんだけどでも1発殴らなきゃ気が済まないから
I love you so much it's impossible, I can't stop loving you, but I won't be satisfied unless I punch you once
しゃあないね しゃあないね 君のせいじゃないもんね
It can't be helped, it can't be helped, it's not your fault, after all
しゃあないね しゃあないね ねんねしたいよね もう一丁
It can't be helped, it can't be helped, you want to sleep, right? One more time!
しゃあないね しゃあないね 泣いても泣いても変わんないね
It can't be helped, it can't be helped, no matter how much you cry, nothing changes
しゃあないね しゃあないね だれも返事しないもんね
It can't be helped, it can't be helped, nobody answers, after all
アンラック アンラック もう そんな傷つけたりしないで
Unluck, unluck, don't hurt others like that anymore
こんなバグだらけの世界になっちゃって
Becoming a world full of bugs like this
ごめんね 大丈夫 安全圏に居ようね 安心な世界に行こうね
I'm sorry. It's alright, let's stay in a safe zone, let's go to a secure world
見捨てないから ずっと 今日も
I won't abandon you, always, today too
アン楽 アン楽 楽 皮を剥いで
Ease, ease, comfort, peeling off skin,
だんだん 希望になれ
gradually becoming hope,
根本的な いい子になるまで 愛してあげるね 大丈夫
until you're fundamentally a good child, I'll love you. It's alright.
どんどん良くで満たして
Fill yourself up more and more,
ブクブクに 恋で肥やして
fatten yourself with love,
骨の髄まで ちゃんと奥まで
down to the marrow, right to the core,
たぁんと I love you
lots of... I love you
Knock it out!
Knock it out! 滅情王
Knock it out! King of Passion
先駆け撃ち最強♡ 望まれて 愛され系
The strongest pioneer shooter ♡ Desired and loved type
魅せられて 光を見せて oh...
Enchanted, show me your light, oh...
欲しがりgame 全て 抜け駆けはしないで
Greedy game, don't jump ahead of everyone with everything
止めないで高鳴り 続いにはツギハギ hate ノイズが心揺らして
Don't stop this throbbing, then patchworked, hate, noise shakes my heart
Knock it out, knocking it out (Yeah, yeah)
飽きてる自慢の光
Tiring of my proud light,
Knock it out, knocking it out (Hey, hey)
それフェイク(笑) はい、「にゃんにゃー♡」 無垢な愛 愛 "イ"会いたいな
That's fake (lol) Yes, "nyan-nyan♡" Innocent love, love, I want to "meet" you
無垢な 愛 愛 “I” 会いたいな
Innocent love, love... I want to see you, "I".
着飾れ ほらピース 裏リーク 堕ちる ふ～
Dress up, look at the peace sign, back leak, falling, fu~
ない ない ない ない 意味ないなー
No, no, no, no, it's meaningless—
ガシンショットン 燃やせプライド
Crash-shotgun, burn your pride!
無個性拝他 待ち構えてた 眩しさは
Soulless xenophobia, waiting eagerly, its brilliance...
狂い始める段取り エゴ 嫌悪
the setup begins to go mad, ego, hatred,
ヘイトへ 鳴呼嫌々々
toward hate, ah, no no no!
聴き飽きたよ 遠吠えも
I'm sick of hearing your howling too.
(Yeah) 夢見てても 起きてなきゃ意味がない
(Yeah) Even if you dream, if you don't wake up, it's meaningless.
(Ah) 傷付いても 立ったステージ
(Ah) Even if wounded, this is the stage I stood on.
彼方まで 音 響かせ
Let the sound echo all the way to the horizon!
踊らせて 強がり 欲張り でかめに say!
Make them dance, acting tough, being greedy, say it loudly!
牙剥け 嘘だらけは done done done da Awake!
Bare your fangs, a world full of lies is done, done, done, da Awake!
愛 愛 愛 愛 キミなんだ
Love, love, love, love, it's you!
笑顔でいれちゃうおまじない ふ〜☆
A spell to keep you smiling, fu~☆
たい たい たい たい 知りたいの キラビやかに Right now!
Want, want, want, want, I want to know brilliantly, right now!
無垢な 愛 愛 “I” 会いたいな
Innocent love, love... I want to see you, "I".
着飾れ ほらピース 裏リーク 堕ちる ふ～
Dress up, look at the peace sign, back leak, falling, fu~
ない ない ない ない 意味ないなー
No, no, no, no, it's meaningless—
ガシンショットン 壊せプライド
Crash-shotgun, destroy your pride!
はい！ということで皆さんびっくりしたでしょう！
Yes! So everyone, you must be surprised!
オリジナル曲、新曲が一気に3曲も出てきて、みんなびっくりしたでしょ！
Three original new songs came out all at once, you guys must be shocked!
えへへへへ。私も嬉しいです。
Hehe. I'm so happy too.
さあこのライブもですね、いよいよ終わりに近づいてきているんでございますが、
Now, this live is finally coming to an end,
重大告知があるんですよ！
but there's a major announcement!
ということですね、そちらVTRを用意しておりますのでぜひみんな見てください！それではどうぞ！
So we have a VTR prepared for that, please everyone take a look! Here it goes!
特報
[Special Report]
天音かなた
Amane Kanata
1st ALBUM 2024/03/13 発売決定
1st ALBUM Releasing March 13, 2024
【作画】平山寛菜
[Character Design: Kanna Hirayama]
【監修】おしおしお
[Character Design: Oshio Shio]
天音かなた 1st ALBUM「Unknown DIVA」 2024/03/13 全国流通にて発売決定
Amane Kanata 1st ALBUM "Unknown DIVA" releasing nationwide on March 13, 2024
全12曲中、完全新曲8曲 全楽曲新規描き下ろし！
12 total tracks, 8 brand new songs, all newly written!
アルバム発売記念企画 その1 毎週土曜日18:00 たそでーない企画!!
Album Release Commemoration Project #1: Every Saturday at 18:00!
アルバム発売記念企画 その2 過去に投稿した歌ってみたのリメイク動画を制作
Album Release Commemoration Project #2: Remakes of past cover songs!
この後 22:00 Giga & TeddyLoid 提供曲「Knock it out!」MV公開
MV release tonight at 22:00 for "Knock it out!" by Giga & TeddyLoid!
ラストチャンスに飢えたつま先が 踊り出すまま駆け出したこの夜空
Starving for a last chance, my tiptoes ran out into this night sky as they danced on.
並のスタンスじゃ響かない 星は宝石の憧れ
Ordinary stances won't resonate. Stars are the yearning of jewels.
浮かぶ涙と汗は血の名残り 目の前でしか泳げなきゃ芝居
Floating tears and sweat are remnants of blood. If you can't swim right before your eyes, it's playacting.
だけどステージが逃がさない いつまでも憧れ 焦がれているよ
But the stage won't let you escape! Forever yearning, burning with desire—
I've never seen such a liar. 生まれつきたっての底なし
I've never seen such a liar. Born with a bottomless nature.
This lie is love. And this lie is a gift to the world.
誰と生きたか思い出して
Remember who you lived with.
わたしが命を賭けるから あげるから
Since I'll risk my life, since I'll give it to you—
あなたは時間をくれたのでしょう? あらゆる望みの総てを叶えたら
You gave me time, didn't you? Once all possible wishes are granted,
ああ果たせたら あなたに会いたい 星に願いをかけて
ah, once fulfilled, I want to meet you, making a wish upon a star.
戻れないから大切にするの？
Is it because we can't go back that we cherish it?
始めないなら高を括るよ
If you're not going to start, you can afford to be smug.
楽になる日はまず来ない
The day you find ease will never come.
日々の中に集まる 悲しい光
Sad light gathering in our days.
生まれつきだってば底なし
It's bottomless since birth.
誰を生きたか忘れちゃった！
I forgot who I lived for!
あなたに命が戻るなら
If life returns to you,
届くなら
if it reaches you,
わたしはどうなろうと構わないのに
even though I wouldn't care what happens to me,
どうやら全ては叶わない
somehow nothing comes true.
叶わないならば
If it doesn't come true,
あなたになりたい
I want to become you.
星は砕け光る
The stars shatter and shine.
わたしが命を掛けるから
Because I am staking my life,
あなたは時間をくれたのでしょう？
you gave me your time, didn't you?
あらゆる望みの全てを叶えたら
If I can grant all of my wishes,
ああ果せたら
Ah, if I can fulfill them,
あなたに会いたい
I want to see you.
星に願いをかけて
Make a wish upon a star.
さあ星の子たちよ よくお眠りなさい
Now, children of the stars, sleep well.
輝きは鈍らない あなたたちならば
If you are the ones whose radiance doesn't dull,
さあ星の子たちよ よく狙いなさい
now, children of the stars, aim well.
またたきを許さない あなたたちならば
If you are the ones who do not permit a blink.
皆さん、天音かなた活動4周年記念のグッズが出ます! わー!
Everyone, merchandise for my 4th anniversary is coming out! Yay!
はい!
Yes!
こんな感じのラインナップ。あ、もうね、あのフルセット購入特典、直筆サイン入りポストカード、数量限定ですのが、
Here's the lineup. The full set purchase bonus includes a hand-signed postcard in limited quantities,
控えさせていただきますとね思いますが、よろしくお願いします。
so please allow me to mention that. Thank you very much.
箔押し複製サイン入りポストカードもね、その後付いてきますので、サインがなくて。
A foil-stamped replica signed postcard will also be included afterwards, so it won't be without a signature.
こんな感じになっています。すごくない?
Here's how it looks. Isn't it amazing?
アクリルスタンド、KNUP Tシャツ、KNUP キャップ、そしてモチーフネックレス付いておりますよ、フルセットすごいです。
Acrylic stand, KNUP T-shirt, KNUP cap, and motif necklace are included! The full set is amazing.
今回みんなね、このTシャツ見てくれ。このTシャツ、あ、でもその前にまずはおくすた!
Everyone, look at this T-shirt. But before that, first is the acrylic stand!
このアクスタ、おしおママが描き下ろしてくださいました！めちゃめちゃかわいいこな。
This acrylic stand was newly illustrated by Oshio Mama! It's super cute.
ほんとにかならずぜひぜひみんなのアクスタ棚とかあると思うんで、飾っていただきたいです。
I really want everyone to display it on your acrylic stand shelves!
そしてKNUP Tシャツ！うわー！これ地雷衣装のTシャツなんですよ！
And the KNUP T-shirt! Wow! This is a landmine outfit T-shirt!
これみんなとねあのねお揃いになるんで、ぜひぜひこちらみんなに着てほしいと思ってます！
Since everyone will match with this, I really want everyone to wear it!
え、そしてこちら天音かなたモチーフネックレス！今回おしおママがデザインしてくれました！
And here is the Amane Kanata motif necklace! This time Oshio Mama designed it!
そして次！ はいこちらキャップです！僕も普段もあのちょっとこういったね黒いね帽子をかぶるんですけど、これからはこちらのKNUPデザインでもうやっていきたいと思います！
And next! Yes, here is the cap! I usually wear black hats like this too, but from now on, I want to go with this KNUP design!
しかもこれ11,500円！12,000円しないですからね！販売価格！あ、残りもこれ税抜きです！
Plus, it's 11,500 yen! It's less than 12,000 yen, right? The selling price! Ah, the rest is excluding tax!
こちらもね概要欄に追加してあるはず、今。なっているので、こちらがなんと20:22時カートオープンとなっておりますので、ぜひぜひ皆さん20:22時に駆け込んでください！
It should be added to the description box now, so the cart opens at 20:22, so everyone please rush over!
そして！20:22には、えー22時より！Knock iT Out!のMVも投稿されます！
And at 22:00, the MV for Knock iT Out! will also be posted!
こちらプレミア公開の時間もありますんで、ま若干ね、あ、こちらに戻ってきましたけれども、こちらもチェックしていただけたら嬉しいなと思っております！みなさんありがとうございます！
There's also the premiere time, so I'd be happy if you check this out too! Thank you everyone!